CURRICULUM VITAE

NAKKINENI MALLIKARJUNA Address: KR PURAM Name

Mobile : 9701598849 **Bangalore** Karnataka 560049

Mail Id harekrishna10024@gmail.com(primary)

harekrishna10020@gmail.com(secondary)

Linkedin: www.linkedin.com/in/nakkineni-mallikarjuna-1b50021bb

Role : Hardware Testing Engineer

CAREER OBJECTIVE:

Aspire to achieve the best standards in the corporate sector through a continuous process of learning, Innovation, integrity, determination and hard work with a view to contribute to the success of the Organization.

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY:

A result-oriented professional with 7.3 years of excellent experience in various Defense (Navy & Army) Warfare & Aerospace electronic equipment systems as Hardware Engineer & production management in Hardware, PCB testing, System Integration, RF Subsystem, RF Module, EMI, EMC, ESS, Reliability Testing, Dielectric testing & Troubleshooting, Automated Tester Troubleshooting, handling multiple customers and suppliers/OEMs, Test downtime reduction, Customer offering, Installation & Execution, Annual maintenance of project systems, Leadership & Team player, Product Support, Production, SAP, BOM, Documentation, Validation & Verification, QA/QC, ECR/ECO, Development & Engineering, Root Cause Analysis, Cost Management, Safety Standards & Compliance. Data Analysis & Reporting, Team Collaboration, Project Management, Equipment and Maintenance, **Sustainability Initiatives**

- > Industrial experience in Embedded PCB Hardware Testing, RF testing, Validation & Verification, Technical
- > Experience in ICT & OCFT Functional Tester and various Automated Tested Equipment
- > Experience in Test RFQ for Test and Measuring equipment and Test fixtures
- > Test & Measuring equipment's handling such as (Oscilloscope, Vector Network Analyzer, Spectrum Analyzer, Digital Multimeter, Power Supply, Function Generator, Signal Generator, Power Meter, Megger, Nodal Impedance Analyzer, Logic Analyzer, LAN Tester, LCR Meter, PCB short locator, DC Electronic Load)
- > EMS experience in Industrial, Commercial and Defense & Aerospace project
- > Test capacity analysis and ICT testers optimization
- > EMS experience in PCBA level and Box build level
- Experience in LINUX & Microsoft Windows operating system
- > Test downtime reduction and analyzing the False failure at various test systems
- Production cycle & Testing
- ➤ Handling multiple projects and customers of Defense & non-Defense
- Working under tight deadlines and with zero defects delivery
- Working with Hardware Engineers, PCB designers and fabricators for sustaining of actual products
- Support the team in debug, troubleshooting and Failure Analysis Investigation & designing
- Strong sense of ownership, ability to work independently and in a team. Have strong communication skills
- Working under tight deadlines with zero defects, Co-ordination with external suppliers/vendors
- On site Installation, Execution, Troubleshooting
- Factory Acceptance Tests, Harbor Acceptance tests, Sea Acceptance Tests
- > SAP Production Planning, CRM (Customer Relationship Management), BOM creation, ECR/ECO creation

- > Time management, Quality management
- Knowledge on Sales & Marketing, Production, Material management, Supply Chain Management
- Pre-sales & post-sales technical support
- Maintaining 100% serviceability of the Annual maintenance contract systems from the customers/clients

HARDWARE TOOLS:

LABVIEW, PYTHON, SCADA, JTAG Emulator, Xilinx ISE, Hyper Terminal, Altera Quartus II, Tera Term, Visual Display, SSH, Putty, Interactive, Test sequencer, Test station, Circuit Tracer, Command Prompt, Any Desk, Simulators, SHARC Debugger, Boundary Scan Tester, Data Acquisition System

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE:

- Hands on experience in Hull mounted SONAR communication system, Hydro pneumatic control system &
 Missile fire control systems of Submarine, RF Missile guidance systems, Missile launching systems, Electronic
 Voting machine, Multi Capacity Encryption & Description unit, Aerospace electronics
- Develop and optimize manufacturing processes
- Analyze production workflows and identify areas for improvement
- Implement Quality Assurance protocols
- Monitor production quality and troubleshoot issues
- Plan and oversee production projects from inception to completion
- Coordinate with different departments, Cross Function Teams & external agencies to ensure project alignment
- Select and maintain production equipment
- Collaborate with maintenance teams to ensure machinery is operational
- Monitor production costs and suggest cost-saving measures
- Analyze cost-effectiveness of different production methods
- Ensure compliance with health and safety regulations
- Collect and analyze production data to identify trends
- Prepare reports for management on production efficiency and issues
- Work closely with Engineers, Technicians, and other CFT's
- Facilitate communication between departments to enhance production efficiency
- Train production staff on new processes and technologies
- Support ongoing professional development for team members
- Implement environmentally sustainable practices in production
- Explore innovations to reduce waste and energy consumption
- PCB level testing, unit level testing, sub system level testing, system level testing, Integration system testing, Automated test equipment testing & Bench level testing, continuity testing, board bring up level, cable harness testing, validation & verification of systems
- Functional testing, Endurance testing, Reliability testing, EMI/EMC testing & troubleshooting, ESS (Environmental stress screening) testing
- Performing EMI/EMC tests like CE (Conduction Emission), RE (Radiation Emission), CS (Conduction Susceptibility), RS (Radiation Susceptibility)
- ESD testing, EFT testing, understand the IEC standards to execute the testing & preparation of report
 Providing technical support to product design teams with respect to EMI/EMC aspects of component selection
 & design suggestions
- Performing ESS tests like Low temperature, High temperature (storage & operational), Thermal cycling,
 Random vibration, Shock test, Drip test, Rain test, Humidity test, HALT & HASS tests, Burn in test
- System, Sub system offering to Navy & Army customers
- Creating test reports for offered items to customers
- Creating Bill of material, Documentation, Bill Book, Routing, FRACAS, Quality Notification, preparing test plans, test
 cases execution, preparing test cases
- Performing technical functions such as assembly, modification, reliability testing and troubleshooting of experimental design circuitry, prototype models, specialized test equipment, tools and test fixtures
- Uses schematics, diagrams, written & verbal descriptions, layouts or plans to perform testing &

- troubleshooting
- Tests and troubleshoots PCB level, system level & component level problems in mechanical, pneumatic, electrical, electronic, electro-mechanical, vacuum system and sub-systems
- familiar with current manufacturing and/or engineering processes and stays informed of any changes in procedures. Assists in the correction of problems
- Performs routine maintenance and shut-down procedures of test equipment
- Compiles test data and records test observations as per the format. Assists in documentation of test procedures
- Coordination and worked with Cross Functional Teams for Product failure Analysis & Development
- Maintaining 5S secure, safe, clean and healthy work environment. Attends required health and safety training, follows safety & security policies, procedures and practices
- Testing of different type of Automated test equipment jig
- Drivers' installation PCI (32-bit)/PCI-E/PCI/X(32-bt,64-bit) & USB 2.0, 3.0 interfaces, SATA
- Good understanding for Product development cycle and product life cycle, providing technical inputs to design teams for new products/correction/upgradation
- Quality inspection of various types of Defence vehicles & integrated electronic systems
- Providing product support activities like testing, troubleshooting at project installation sites of Navy & Army (Army Surface vehicles, Navy under water vehicles)
- Receiving faulty items from the sites, resolving the issues of various faulty sub systems and sending back to customer sites
- Maintaining complaints data in CRM application of various systems & resolving it over phone & visiting sites
- Worked on Compliance Agency Certifications (CE, FCC, UL, CSA, NMI)
- Good knowledge on KPI, RMA, FOD
- Safety Management System ISO 9100 REV.D, IEC 61000, ISO 9001, MIL STD 461 E, MIL STD 461F, JSSSSS MIL GRADE & MIL 1553B standards, 7QC tools, CAN, SNMP, SNTP, SFTP, MODBUS, serial, TCP, UART, SPI, I2C, ETHERNET, RS-232, RS-485
- Maintaining lab equipment 5S standards, & calibration of electronic measuring instruments & ATEs
- Good understanding on ROHS, REACH, UKAS. Assembly and Electrical drawings of various electronic systems
- Knowledge on semiconductors manufacturing process, Networking basics, Microcontrollers & Microprocessors
- Visiting OEM places for system/sub system/module clearance
- Maintaining inward goods, testing & preparing documents
- Technical coordination for field complaints, problems understanding, Product testing/Root cause identification, FEMA, coordinate with the design teams for problem rectification, Initiate and manage Root cause Analysis for product issues or problems
- Expertise as manufacturing engineer, working knowledge on production, assembling, quality inspection
- Involved & worked in in house activities like shipping systems, dockets collection, material gate pass, receiving electronic equipment from the sites
- Power systems ACOS, Isolation transformer, power distribution unit, AC-DC, DC-DC testing, component selection

MY STRENGTHS:

- > Positive Attitude, Confident & Determined, Good verbal & written communication skills
- Quick learner, Self-driven, Ability to work independently, Time management
- Good decision making, Professionalism & strong work ethic
- Hard work, smart work & dedicated team player
- Interested to learn and work on new technologies
- Maintaining clean work environment

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

- Senior Associate Manufacturing Engineer, Collins Aerospace Bangalore 12-Jun-2024 to Till Date
- Component Engineer at element14, Bangalore 08-Nov-2023 to 07-Jun-2024
- ➤ Hardware Testing Engineer, Bharat Electronics Limited Bangalore 23-Mar-2017 to 25-Feb-2023

EDUCATION DETAILS:

B. TECH: (Electronics & Communication Engineering) - May 2016 – 78.26 % (Distinction)

(Jawaharlal Nehru Technological University Hyderabad

DIPLOMA: (Electronics & Communication Engineering) - April 2013 – 78.14 % (Distinction)

(State Board of Technical Education & Training Andhra Pradesh)

SSC (10th class): March 2010 – 88.33% (Distinction) (Board of Secondary Education Andhra Pradesh)

PROJECTS:

- AKSHAY & SHARANG (Hydro pneumatic control system & missile fire control system)
- USHUS (Submarine sound navigation and ranging)
- > HUMSA NG (Hull mounted SONAR communication system)
- AKASH MISSILE SYSTEM (Surface to Air missile launching system & target detection of aircraft enemies)
- RF SEEKER (Missile guidance system, Surface to air)
- MULTI CAPACITY ENCRYPTION & DECRYPTION UNIT (Securing data safely with coding)
- > VVPAT, EVM (Voter Verifiable Paper Audit Trail, Electronic voting machine)
- G7K SLAT FLAT ELECTRONIC CONTROL UNIT
- ➤ KC390 FCEM FLIGHT CONTROL ELECTRONIC MODULE

CERTIFICATIONS:

- Industrial training & worked on Embedded systems at JBS Power systems Hyderabad (15-05-2012 to 15-11-2012)
- Certification in Poly skills & Designing of Analog & Digital circuits, conducted by skill development center Govt. Polytechnic Anantapur (Dec 2011 to March 2012)
- Certificate of Training on Technical Support & Testing for Embedded systems at customer sites (21-01-2012 to 22-01-2022)
- Certificate of completion in Safety Management System 20-06-2024
- ➤ Certificate of completion in Code of Conduct Course: Culture of Integrity 26-07-2024
- ➤ Certificate of completion Conflicts of Interest: Putting Company Interests First 26-07-2024
- Certificate of Completion in UTC EHS Contractor Coordinator Training Level I 30-07-2024

PERSONAL DETAILS:

Date of birth : 31-Aug-1994

Sex : Male
Marital status : Un-Married
Religion : Hindu
Nationality : Indian

Languages known : English, Hindi, Telugu, Kannada

SELF DECLARATION:

I do hereby declare that the above information is true to the best of my knowledge and belief

Regards, Nakkineni Mallikarjuna